Guide to the Jack Gelber Papers 1938-2002 (Bulk 1957-1999) MSS.146
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries A
    - Aaron, Steve, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abzug, Hon. Bella S., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Accent, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Actor's Academy West, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Actors Anonymous, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Actor's Theatre, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Actor's Workshop of the San Francisco Drama Guild, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The African Arts Fund, Inc., 1985-1993, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Albee, Edward, 1959-[1982] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Albert, Carolyn, 1982, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alberts, Frank Alberts, Jane, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Allen, L., Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Allen, Lewis M., 1960-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      General note
      The contents of this folder include unsigned copies of an agreement regarding the film version of "The Connection" sent by Sidamon-Eristoff, Morrison, Warren, and Ecker on behalf of Mystic Fire Productions, Inc.
    - Almeida, Maria de Lourdes Biga de, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Almeida Theatre Company, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The American Conservatory Theatre, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - American Jewish Theatre, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned agreement offering Gelber the position of Director in a production of "Born Guilty" by Ari Roth
    - American National Theatre, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The American Place Theatre, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned agreement offering Gelber the position of Director in a production of "Remember the Alamo" by Barry Litvack; See Also: Konecky, Ronald S. (Series IA, Box 6, Folder 344), Melinda (Series IB, Box 14, Folder 823)
    - American Premiere Stage, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      See Also: Cacaci, Joe (Series IA, Box 2, Folder 102)
    - The American Theatre Company in Aspen, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      This folder includes a signed copy of a contract offering Gelber the position of "Playwriting Teacher"
    - Amherst College, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Anderson, Robert, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Andrucki, Marty, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Applause Theatre Book Publishers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Arena Stage, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Ari, Mark, 1986-1994, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arkin, Alan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Author's Guild, Inc., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Arlecchino Teaterforlag Bertil Boden, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      See Also: Teaterforlaget SCALA (Series IA, Box 11, Folder 657)
    - Artisjus Agence Litteraire, Theatrale, et de Musique, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Arts of the Theatre Foundation, Inc., [1957]-1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Ashley, Leonard R. N., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Atelier Zero, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Atlantic Center for the Arts, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      The contents of this folder include a signed "Master Artist in Residence" agreement
    - Atomic Energy Information Service, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Austin, Lyn, 1966-1968, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
      See Also: General Artists Corporation (Series IA, Box 4, Folder 248)
    - Austin, Paul, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - B., Julie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - B., Peter Pamela, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Balding, Ivor David, 1965-1993, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
      See Also: "Clippings and Notes" (Series IE, Box 22, Folder 945)
    - Baldner, Thomas, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bank, Rosemarie K., Dr., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - [Barnes, Averill], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Baron, Sandy, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Barr, Richard, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bartle, Barry, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - BAT Theatre Company, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Baumbach, Georgia Baumbach, Jonathan, 1979, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Bay Area Theatre Critics Circle, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Baz, Beatriz E., 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - BC Research, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Beckerman, Bernard, 1965-1970, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
      See Also: "Sleep" Materials (Series IIF, Box 23, Folder 952)
    - Belber, Stephen, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Belgrave, Cynthia, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Bennett, Elsie M., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Bentley, Eric, 1972-1979, Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Bentley, Jo, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Berlin, Adam, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Berkeley Jewish Theatre, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - [Bernal], Al [Bernal], Joyce, 1972-1990, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Bernheim, Alain Bernheim, Michael, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Bernheim, Kurt, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bibliographisches Istitut, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Big Apple Circus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Bindlestiff Studio, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - [Bingos, Robert], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Bird, Tom, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Bishop's University, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Bitter Sweet Productions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Blaber, Ralph, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      The contents of this folder include a clipping of "Review: 'Live' Drama is at the Circle Art," Ralph Blaber, The Times-Review (Fort Erie, Ontario, Canada), November 8, 1962
    - Blumenthal and Lynne, Counselors at Law, 1990-1992, Undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Board of Cooperative Educational Services, Nassau County, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Booker, Bob Foster, George, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Boston University Libraries, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Bowen, Gary, Undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Brandt, Carl, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Branigan, Alan, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Bravo, Ricardo, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Brechner, Roger, 1982, Undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Brennan, Mary E., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Brennan, Scott W., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Brevoort, Gregg W., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Brodsky, Michael, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Bromberg, Conrad, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Bromka, Elaine, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Brook, Natasha, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Brook, Peter, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "The Cannes Film Festival," The Observer, May 14, 1961, "Dateline: Your World: The Connection," Joseph Barry, New York Post, July 11, 1961; "The Connection," Dwight Macdonald, Esquire, September 1961; "Expect N.Y. Nix for Unexpurgated 'Connection'-Distributor Will Appeal, Variety, September 6, 1961; "The Connection (L'intermedario)," Festival, July 28 [1961]; "'The Connection' is Powerful Fix," Lawrence Thaw, Jr., London American, July 15, 1961; "At The Pictures: The Connection," Richard Mallet, Punch, November 22, 1961; "One Trick Too Many," Bamber Gascoigne, The Spectator, March 3, 1961; "Coming of Cowboy," H.A.L. Craig, New Statesman, March 3, 1961
    - Brooks, Jeremy, 1967-1969, Undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Brooks, John B., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Brown, Jack, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Brown, Kenneth H., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Brunet, Alain, Undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Brustein, Robert, 1959-1993 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Bryden, Bill, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Buckley, Hon. James L., Javits, Hon. Jacob K., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Buettner-Janusch, John, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Burroughs, William, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - The Bush Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - [Butler], William, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Cacaci, Joe, 1977-1988 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Caleb, Rufus, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - California State University Los Angeles, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Campolo, Robert, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corp., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Canby, Vincent, 1984-1994 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Carson, [Shayne], 1968 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Casa de las Americas, 1964-1970, Undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
      See Also: [Desnoes], Maria Rosa (Series IA, Box 3, Folder 172); Festival de Teatro Latinoamericano (Series IIE, Box 21, Folder 934)
    - Cavalier Magazine, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Center for Cuban Studies, 1974, Undated (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Center Theatre Group, Mark Taper Forum, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - El Centro Cubano del Instituto del Teatro, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - El Centro de Artes Creativas de Cuernavaca, A.C., Undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Chartoff-Winkler Productions, Ltd., 1970, Undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned contract regarding a screenplay entitled "Cry of Whiteness"
    - Chase, Geoffrey, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Chelsea Theatre Center of Brooklyn, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Cherches, Peter N., Undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Chessler, Charles, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Childs, Prentiss, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Chin, Frank, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Christensen, Claude, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Christiansen, Rick C., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Circle Art Theatre, [1962] (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Circle in the Square Theatre, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Circle Repertory Theatre, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - City Lights Theatre Company, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - The City of New York Department of Sanitation, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - City University of New York, 1964-1999, Undated (Box 2, Folder 130)
      See Also: Dorsky, Morris (Series IA, Box 3, Folder 184), Jon (Series IB, Box 13, Folder 807), Peter (Series IB, Box 14, Folder 840), "Starters" (Annotated Typescript) and Notes" (Series II,I Box 27, Folder 983), "'Gibby' Current Casting" (Series IIJ, Box 31, Folder 1008)
    - Clark, Barbara, Undated (Box 2, Folder 131)
      This folder also holds a note from Retta Blaney
    - Clay, Mel, 1991, Undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Cleland, Charles F., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Clinton, President William Jefferson, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Coe, John, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Cohen, Alexander Cohen, Hildy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Colby College, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Columbia University, 1965-1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 138)
      The contents of this folder include a copy of a signed "Final Grade Sheet" for Gelber's Playwriting Introductory Course I; See Also: Beckerman, Bernard (Series IA, Box 1, Folder 54), Manning, Kara (Series IA, Box 7, Folder 411), "Sleep" Materials (Series IIF, Box 23, Folder 952)
    - The Column Theatre and Studio, [1993] (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Commentary, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Company of Angels, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Condee, William F., 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Connolly, John P., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Conroy, Frank, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - El Consejo Nacional de Cultura, Republica de Cuba, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - A Contemporary Theatre, Inc., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Conti, Valerie M., 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Conway, Kevin, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Cooperativa Nuova Scena, 1982-1984, Undated (Box 3, Folder 149)
      For Oversize Material See: Series IA Oversize, Map Case, Drawer 3G, Folder 1191
    - Coover, Robert, 1972-1979, Undated (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Cope, Jackson I., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Corrales, Elizabeth, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Coryell, Julie, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Crawford, Lynda, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Creative Management Associates, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Crews, John, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Cricket Theatre, Undated (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Crilly, Sister Mary, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 158)
      See Also: Lew (Series IB, Box 13, Folder 815)
    - Criterion Books, Inc., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Crommie, Richard, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Cue Magazine, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Dartmouth College, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Daubney, Peter, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - [David, Lane], Undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Davis, Melissa, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Delainey, Victor, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Delgado, Mario, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 167)
      See Also: Grove Press (Series IA, Box 5, Folder 263)
    - De Meo, Lon, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Denver Center Theatre Company, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 169)
      The item is annotated with the name "Larry Eilenberg"
    - Denver Model City Resident Cultural Center, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Desani, G.V., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - [Desnoes], Edmundo [Desnoes], Maria Rosa (nee Almendros), 1964-1977, Undated (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Destro, Ron, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Dexter and the Rollerrocker Showstoppers USA, Undated (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Dial, Bill, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Dietz, Susan, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Dilia Theatrical and Literary Agency, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Disc Management Services Group, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Doctor Connie Ricono Rappresentante di Autori Drammatici, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Doctor Jan Van Lowen, Ltd., 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Doe-Eye Productions, Ltd., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 181)
      See Also: Gelber, Jack (Series IA, Box 4, Folder 244)
    - Dominique, P., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Donohue, James R., 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Dorsky, Morris, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Doyle, Julie, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - The Drama Review (MIT Press), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 186)
      This folder also holds a signed "Transfer of Copyright" agreement for "Julian Beck, Businessman" by Jack Gelber
    - The Dramatist's Guild, Inc., 1965-1992 (Box 3, Folder 187)
      See Also: Gerald (Series 1B, Box 13, Folder 794)
    - Drozdovsky, Alexei Anatolievich, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Dubbe, P.D., 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Dundy, Elaine, 1995, Undated (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Dunham, Mike, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - East Coast Arts at Wildcliff, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 192)
      The contents of this folder include unsigned copies of a contract regarding "Big Shot;" See Also: Cacaci, Joe (Series IA, Box 2, Folder 102), "Gibby Current Casting" (Series IIK Box 30, Folder 1008); For Oversize Material See: Series IA Oversize, Box 48, Folder 1192
    - Eastlake, William, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - The East-West Culture Learning Institute, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 194)
      See Also: "The Playwright's Dilemma" (Typescript) (Series IIR, Box 44, Folder 1155)
    - The Ecco Press, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Edelson, Eve, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Edinburgh International Festival, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Edition Wilhelm Hansen/Chester Music NY, Inc., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Edmiston, Susan, Undated (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Ehrmann, Hans, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - [Elmslie, Kenward], [1970] (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - [Ely, Herndon], 1997 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Emerson College, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 204)
      See Also: Cacaci, Joe ( Series IA, Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Emery Collegiate Institute, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - EMI Films, Inc., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - The English Stage Company, Ltd., 1977-1998 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Ensemble Productions Pty. Ltd., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Ensemble Studio Theatre, 1977-1994 (Box 4, Folder 209)
      The contents of this folder include agreements offering Gelber the position of Director in productions of the following plays: "The House of Ramon Iglesia" by Jose Rivera (signed), "The Dolphin Position" by Percy Granger (signed), "Mink on a Gold Hook" by James Ryan (signed), "Dream of a Blacklisted Actor" by Conrad Bromberg (unsigned), "Magic Valley" by Jack Gelber (signed), "The Hearth" by Alexander R. Scott (unsigned), "George Washington Dances" by David Margulies (unsigned), and "I'm With Ya Duke" by Herb Gardner (signed); See Also: International Creative Management (Series IA, Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Erdreich, Marjorie Hauptman, William, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Erie Community College, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Esquire, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Esterman, Laura, Undated (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theatre Center, 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 214)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract regarding "Starters;" See Also: George (Series IB, Box 13, Folder 793)
    - Evans, Ray M., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Experimental Theatre Club of San Antonio, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 216)
      The contents of this folder include a signed contract regarding "The Connection"
    - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, Inc. Book Publishers, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Fay, Gloden M., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Feiffer, Judy Feiffer, Jules, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Feldman, Peter, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Finn, James, Undated (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Fischer, Jules, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Fisher, Jules, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Fitzgerald, Frances, Undated (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Fitzgibbons, Mark, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 225)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "Savoring Surreal Success," by Joseph C. Koenenn, New York Newsday, June 1, 1990; "A Modernized Hamlet Amid One-Act Plays," by Mel Gussow, The New York Times, June 1, 1990
    - Forbes, Barbara, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - The Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Franks, Andrew J., Undated (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Fratti, Mario, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 229)
      The contents of this folder include a clipping of "Modern Italian Theatre," by Unknown Author, Unknown Publication, Undated
    - Freedman, Dr. Roselyn L., 1984 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Friedman, Bob H., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Friedman, Bruce J., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Fried-Miller, Gina, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Frolich, Pea Heilmeyer, Jens, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Furze, Sue, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - G., Sam, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Gale Research International Ltd., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 237)
      The contents of this folder include photocopies of "Jack Gelber," from Contemporary Dramatists 1993, Kate Berney, ed., (London: St. James Press, 1993) and "Jack Gelber" by Vincent F. Petronella from unknown book.
    - Garen, Leo, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - Garis, Mab, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - Garry, Josph J., Jr., 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 240)
      The contents of this folder include the following clippings: "Theatre and Life-The Connection" by Michael Birtwistle, Cleveland After Dark, November 19,1969; "CSU's Unusual Theatre Accents Shock Drama," by Peter Bellamy, The Plain Dealer, November 18, 1969; "CSU to Debut Play, Theatre," by Peter Bellamy, The Plain Dealer, n.d.; "Prof Signs to Direct Aristophanes Play on Broadway" by Peter Bellamy, The Plain Dealer, April 25,1972.
    - Gassner, John, 1963, Undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - Gavronsky, Serge, Undated (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - Gelber, Carol, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - Gelber, Jack, 1957-1999, Undated (Box 4, Folder 244)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned agreement addressed to the Establishment Theatre Company regarding an unnamed play along with the following enclosures: a typescript entitled "Jack Gelber K.O.'s a Chinese Commie, Maybe" by Jack Gelber, revision notes for an untitled article regarding Cuba, a series of letters exchanged between Gelber and Herbert Leonard Enterprises Inc., and "'The Faith Healer' by William Vaughn Moody: A Precis for Television" by Jack Gelber; See Also: United States Department of the Treasury (Series IA, Box 11, Folder 687), "'Chambers' Revised" (Two Typescripts) (Series IIL, Box 33, Folder 1031); "Mother of the Bride, Working Copy" (Annotated Typescript) Notes, and a Flyer (Series IIQ, Box 41, Folder 1114); "By the Way, My Name is Roger Soames" (Typescript and Two Pages from a Manuscript Version) (Series IIR, Box 42, Folder 1129); Small Notebook (Series IIS, Box 44, 1170)
    - Gelber, [Martin] G., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Gelber, Molly, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - Gelfman, Samuel W., 1965-1988 (Box 4, Folder 247)
      This folder also includes a letter from [Walter Ken] of the New York Herald Tribune
    - General Artists Corporation, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 248)
      The contents of this folder include photocopies of signed and unsigned contracts with Arthur Kopit, Lyn Austin, and the International Famous Agency, Inc. regarding "Indians" by Arthur Kopit; See Also Gelfman, Samuel W. (Series IA, Box 4, Folder 248)
    - [Gilbert, Lon], 1976 (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - Gillin, Don, [1961] (Box 4, Folder 250)
      The contents of this folder include the following clipping: "La Droga e lo Squallore in un Film d'Avanguardia," Luigi Gilliberto, Il Gazzettino, August 25, 1961
    - Gilman, Richard, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 251)
    - Goddard College, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 252)
      The contents of this folder include an unsigned "Visiting Artist" contract
    - Gold Coast of Louisiana Ltd., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 253)
    - Goldcrest Mission, Limited, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - Goldstein, Dave, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - The Goodman Theatre, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 256)
      See Also: Whittlesley, Peregrine (Series IA, Box 12, Folder 725)
    - Gorman, Joseph, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 257)
    - Gray, Edward, Captain, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 258)
      This correspondent was also known as "Buffalo Bill II;" See Also: "Indians" Clippings (Series IIP, Box 36, Folder 1061) for the following clippings: "England's Buffalo Bill Visits Grave of Buffalo Bill Cody," Rocky Mountain News, Oct. 11, 1962 and "Buffalo Bill Walks Again," by William Longgood, New York World Telegram and Sun, Oct. 5, 1962
    - [Gray], Sam, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 259)
    - Grodin, Charles, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - Grogan, Sheila, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - Grosbard, Ulu, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Grove Press, 1961-1990 (Box 5, Folder 263)
      See Also: Seaver, Richard (Series IA, Box 10, Folder 584); This folder also includes messages sent to Grove Press regarding Gelber's work from various producers, theatres, and writers including World Literature Publishing House, United Campus Christian Fellowship's Theatre of Involvement, Centre d'Etudes Theatrales, University of Winnipeg Student Theatre Association, The Back Alley Theatre, and Sidney Homan.
    - Gruber, Sol, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - The Guthrie Theatre, 1984-1990 (Box 5, Folder 265)
      See Also: Gelber, Jack (Series IA, Box 4, Series 244)
    - Gutman, Judith Mara, Undated (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - H., Tim, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 267)
      The contents of this folder include a clipping, "Dmitri Volkogonov, 67, Historian Who Debunked Heroes, Dies," Alessandra Stanley, New York Times, December 7, 1995.
    - The Hamlet, Undated (Box 5, Folder 268)
      See Also: Litvinoff, Seymour (Series IA, Box 6, Folder 378)
    - Hampstead Theatre Club, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 269)
      See Also: Rudman, Michael (Series IA, Box 9, Folder 557); Burke (Series 1B, Box 13 Folder 771)
    - Hansell, Susan, 1996-1997, Undated (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - Harder, Jim, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - Hardy, Gordon Hardy, Lillian, Undated (Box 5, Folder 272)
    - Harrison, Tony, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Hartford Stage Company, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - Hastings, Paul, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - [Haufreilit]; Marcia, Undated (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - Hefter, David, Undated (Box 5, Folder 277)